<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C_LoadBalancing on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/c_loadbalancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C_LoadBalancing on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/c_loadbalancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantingTrees</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Described by Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Kolinkat2001). Two introduction questions presented by Steven Bogaerts as part of his &amp;ldquo;real-life analogies&amp;rdquo; (Bogaerts2014, Bogaerts2017).
No public description avaialable. See Details section for more information.
 Details Start with some generals questions from Steven Bogaerts:
 &amp;ldquo;If I can shovel my driveway in 1 hour, how long would you expect it to take if someone equally capable were to help me?&amp;rdquo;
  &amp;ldquo;If one person can dig a hole with a shovel in 100 seconds, how long will it take for 10 people to dig that hole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindOldestPenny</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 13:09:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava, with consultation from Brett A Becker.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Similar Activities FindSmallestCard, FindYoungestStudent
 Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to find the oldest penny in a pile of pennies. This is first done sequentially, with one student trying to determine the oldest penny in a group of 50 pennies. Next, two students are employed, with each student getting a bag of 25 pennies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JigsawPuzzle</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/jigsawpuzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 13:12:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/jigsawpuzzle/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - Overview, Slides 45-52.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)   Variations It is theoretically possible to &amp;ldquo;act out&amp;rdquo; the analogy by using an actual puzzle. However, the puzzle needs to be small enough to enable students to complete the puzzle in a reasonable amount of time. This variation is described in (Neeman2006):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
 Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CandySorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/candysorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:23:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/candysorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF   CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage Parallel Decomposition (Core Tier 1, Core Tier 2) 1. Core Tier 1: Explain why synchronization is necessary in a specific parallel program. [Usage]
2. Core Tier 1: Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
4. Core Tier 2: Parallelize an algorithm by applying task-based decomposition. [Usage]
Parallel Performance (Elective) 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>