<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A_DataParallel on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/a_dataparallel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A_DataParallel on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/a_dataparallel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArrayAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
 Details Students sitting at desks represent &amp;ldquo;threads&amp;rdquo; on individual cores. Each student has a piece of paper on their desk representing local memory. Prior to the activity, the instructor writes an array on the board, filled with random values (limit 1 through 10 for ease of addition), with indices written underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
 Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArraysinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 11:58:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage PD/Parallel Decomposition Core Tier1, Core Tier2 2. Core Tier 1:Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
5.\ Core Tier 2:Parallelize an algorithm by applying data-parallel decomposition. [Usage]
TCPP Coverage Programming Topics  Apply Data parallel: Be able to write a correct data parallel program for shared-memory machines and get speedup, should do an exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>