<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PD_5 on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/pd_5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PD_5 on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/pd_5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantingTrees</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Described by Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Kolinkat2001). Two introduction questions presented by Steven Bogaerts as part of his &amp;ldquo;real-life analogies&amp;rdquo; (Bogaerts2014, Bogaerts2017).
No public description avaialable. See Details section for more information.
Details Start with some generals questions from Steven Bogaerts:
 &amp;ldquo;If I can shovel my driveway in 1 hour, how long would you expect it to take if someone equally capable were to help me?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;If one person can dig a hole with a shovel in 100 seconds, how long will it take for 10 people to dig that hole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StuffingEnvelopes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:10:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
Details Prior to the activity, students should be assigned to teams of four. The goal is to discuss different strategies for completing the stack of preparing letters for mailing. In doing the activity, students learn about domain (data) decomposition vs task decomposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MoreProcessorsNotAlwaysBetter</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to write the statement &amp;ldquo;More Processors Are Not Always The Best&amp;rdquo;, along with the indices of each letter.
 Sequential phase. In the sequential phase, a single student is instructed to first write the statement show above (task 1) and then write the index associated with each letter (0 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DesertIslandsAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 15:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Distributed Multiprocessing&amp;rdquo;, Slides 19-25.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  The following questions from (Neeman2006) can be used to stimulate discussion:
 Suppose that each student is on his or her own island far away from everyone else. Are any of them aware of anyone else? Do they know who is at the other end of the phone line?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArraysinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 11:58:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage PD/Parallel Decomposition Core Tier1, Core Tier2 2. Core Tier 1:Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
5.\ Core Tier 2:Parallelize an algorithm by applying data-parallel decomposition. [Usage]
TCPP Coverage Programming Topics  Apply Data parallel: Be able to write a correct data parallel program for shared-memory machines and get speedup, should do an exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>