<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C_DistributedMemory on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/c_distributedmemory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C_DistributedMemory on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:20:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/c_distributedmemory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MessagePassingAcrobats</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/messagepassingacrobats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:20:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/messagepassingacrobats/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Steven K. Andrianoff and David B. Levine
No link to independent description available. See &amp;ldquo;Details&amp;rdquo; for more details.
 Details The instructor plays the role of the main program, and students play the role of one or more acrobats.
  The instructor chooses a few student volunteers to be &amp;ldquo;acrobats&amp;rdquo;. It is very important that the instructor knows the names of the students (and that they have different names).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ByzantineGenerals</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/byzantinegenerals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:02:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/byzantinegenerals/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by William S. Lloyd (Lloyd1994)
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Lloyd1994) for additional details.
 Details Students learn of the classic Byzantine Generals problem by acting out scenarios.
The Byzantine Generals problem is a classic description of the consensus problem in distributed computing, where many independent processes must agree on a &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; value for a particular measurement (especially in the case where some processes become unreliable due to faults).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DesertIslandsAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 15:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Distributed Multiprocessing&amp;rdquo;, Slides 19-25.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  The following questions from (Neeman2006) can be used to stimulate discussion:
 Suppose that each student is on his or her own island far away from everyone else. Are any of them aware of anyone else? Do they know who is at the other end of the phone line?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
 Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MatrixAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 09:38:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). In a separate paper (Kitchen1992), the notion of adding numbers in a matrix to illustrate master/worker is alluded to, but not discussed in depth.
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by author (Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
 Details Moore describes how to use Matrix Addition to describe the differences between shared memory vs distributed memory systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>