<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>movement on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/senses/movement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in movement on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/senses/movement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArrayAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
Details Students sitting at desks represent &amp;ldquo;threads&amp;rdquo; on individual cores. Each student has a piece of paper on their desk representing local memory. Prior to the activity, the instructor writes an array on the board, filled with random values (limit 1 through 10 for ease of addition), with indices written underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelGarbageCollection</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelgarbagecollection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:36:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelgarbagecollection/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Paulo A.G. Sivilotti and Scott Pike
Paper and poster available online:
Details See paper for details. In summary, this activity presents a directed graph with a distinguished vertex (labeled the root). Vertices are connected to each other with some number of edges. The end-goal is determine the set of reachable vertices from the root (&amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo;) and distinguish them from the set of non-reachable vertices (&amp;ldquo;garbage&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NondeterministicSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/nondeterministicsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:39:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/nondeterministicsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Paulo A.G. Sivilotti and Scott Pike
Paper and poster available online:
Details See paper and poster for full details. A high level summary is provided below:
 A group of students are chosen to represent elements in an array. Each student is given a sign/sticker that indicates their position in the array. Each student is also given an index card with a random integer value on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MoreProcessorsNotAlwaysBetter</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to write the statement &amp;ldquo;More Processors Are Not Always The Best&amp;rdquo;, along with the indices of each letter.
 Sequential phase. In the sequential phase, a single student is instructed to first write the statement show above (task 1) and then write the index associated with each letter (0 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelRadixSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelradixsort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 10:30:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelradixsort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Adam Rifkin (1994). No web-link to independent description available. However, (Sivilotti2003) employed the exercise in a summer workshop for middle school girls, and provided a write-up of the activity and slides associated with the activity at his website
 Slides (includes other activities) PPT 1 Page Synopsis PDF  See papers (Rifkin1994, Sivilotti2003) for additional details.
Similar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, sortingNetwork, cardsorting
Other activities by (Rifki1994, Sivilotti2003) Rifkin1994: oddEvenTranspositionSort</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ByzantineGenerals</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/byzantinegenerals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:02:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/byzantinegenerals/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by William S. Lloyd (Lloyd1994)
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Lloyd1994) for additional details.
Details Students learn of the classic Byzantine Generals problem by acting out scenarios.
The Byzantine Generals problem is a classic description of the consensus problem in distributed computing, where many independent processes must agree on a &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; value for a particular measurement (especially in the case where some processes become unreliable due to faults).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SweetenJuice</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sweetenjuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:07:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sweetenjuice/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Mordechai Ben-Ari and Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Ben-Ari1999)
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Ben-Ari1999) for additional details.
Details The paper uses dramatizations to help students understand algorithmic execution. The paper only describes one such lesson, which is used to introduce the concept of mutual exclusion. The following is a rough summary of the exercise in (Ben-Ari1999):
Two students volunteer to be robots. A drinking glass is placed at a visible point in the classroom, purporting to contain &amp;ldquo;juice&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DesertIslandsAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 15:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Distributed Multiprocessing&amp;rdquo;, Slides 19-25.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  The following questions from (Neeman2006) can be used to stimulate discussion:
 Suppose that each student is on his or her own island far away from everyone else. Are any of them aware of anyone else? Do they know who is at the other end of the phone line?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MatrixAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 09:38:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). In a separate paper (Kitchen1992), the notion of adding numbers in a matrix to illustrate master/worker is alluded to, but not discussed in depth.
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by author (Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
Details Moore describes how to use Matrix Addition to describe the differences between shared memory vs distributed memory systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CompanyAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/companyanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 17:02:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/companyanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Nasser Giacaman (Giacaman2012).
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Giacaman2012) for details.
Details The company analogy is used to introduce multicore systems:
 The processor is a &amp;ldquo;company&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;desks&amp;rdquo; representing multiple cores. Students (&amp;ldquo;employees&amp;rdquo;) are assigned/hired to sit at a desk to do work, representing threads (or processes). Work is written on &amp;ldquo;job cards&amp;rdquo; and represent tasks/runnables to be executed.
  To illustrate (under)utilization and resource contention/context switching:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PBJinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pbjinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:19:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pbjinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage Communication and Coordination (Core Tier 1) 2. Core Tier 1: Give an example of an ordering of accesses among concurrent activities (e.g., program with a data race) that is not sequentially consistent. [Familiarity]
TCPP Topics Coverage Programming Topics  Comprehend Deadlocks: Understand what a deadlock is, and methods for detecting and preventing them
 Know Data Races: Know what a data race is, and how to use synchronization to prevent it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArraysinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 11:58:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage PD/Parallel Decomposition Core Tier1, Core Tier2 2. Core Tier 1:Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
5.\ Core Tier 2:Parallelize an algorithm by applying data-parallel decomposition. [Usage]
TCPP Coverage Programming Topics  Apply Data parallel: Be able to write a correct data parallel program for shared-memory machines and get speedup, should do an exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SortingNetwork</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:31:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link CSUnplugged.Org
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage N/A
TCPP Coverage Algorithms:  Know Sorting: Observe several sorting algorithms for varied platforms &amp;mdash; together with analyses. Parallel merge sort is the simplest example, but equally simple alternatives for rings and meshes might be covered also; more sophisticated algorithms might be covered in more advanced courses (1 hour)  Recommended Courses  K-12: CSUnplugged recommends this as a K-12 activity. CS1/CS2/DSA: The activity can be used to introduce students to parallel sorting concepts in undergraduate courses, but is inappropriate for large classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>