<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CC_2 on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/cc_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CC_2 on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 17:54:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/cc_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ConcertTickets</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/concerttickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 17:54:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/concerttickets/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Kolinkat2001). Modified for a CS1 audience by Gary Lewandowski, Dennis Bouvier, Robert McCartney, Kate Sanders, and Beth Simon in 2007 (Lewandowski2007, Lewandowski2010)
No on-line resources available. See details for description.
Details CS1 Use-Case The following scenario is presented to students entering CS1 on their first day (Lewandowski2010):
 Suppose a Ticket Sale Company sells concert tickets in the following way: When a customer calls and asks for a n seats, the seller (1) finds the n best available seats; (2) marks those n seats as unavailable; and (3) deals with customer payment options and either e-mails ticket receipt or sends tickets to the Will Call Box Office (lets customer pick up tickets day of show).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ByzantineGenerals</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/byzantinegenerals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 14:02:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/byzantinegenerals/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by William S. Lloyd (Lloyd1994)
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Lloyd1994) for additional details.
Details Students learn of the classic Byzantine Generals problem by acting out scenarios.
The Byzantine Generals problem is a classic description of the consensus problem in distributed computing, where many independent processes must agree on a &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; value for a particular measurement (especially in the case where some processes become unreliable due to faults).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>