<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>touch on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/senses/touch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in touch on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:10:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/senses/touch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>StuffingEnvelopes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:10:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
Details Prior to the activity, students should be assigned to teams of four. The goal is to discuss different strategies for completing the stack of preparing letters for mailing. In doing the activity, students learn about domain (data) decomposition vs task decomposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoinFlip</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/coinflip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:00:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/coinflip/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Andrew Kitchen, Nan Schaller and Paul Tyman (Kitchen1992).
No link to independent description available. See Details for a synopsis.
Details The goal of this activity is to help students visualize the difference between execution on a SIMD architecture vs a MIMD architecture. Each student plays a processor and is given a coin.
They are presented with the following algorithm:
1. flip coin. 2. check if heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PipelineSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pipelinesort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 12:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pipelinesort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). It was also mentioned in (Kitche1992), but (Maxim1990) is listed as a reference.
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Similiar Exercises: Sorting: OddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, CardSorting, SortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal of this exercise is to illustrate how sorting can occur in a stream/pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/paralleladdition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 15:43:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/paralleladdition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994)
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): FindSmallestCard, CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, SieveOfErastothenes, AddLargeNumbers
Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to add a series of 16 random numbers. Each student is given a piece of paper (representing local memory) that only they have access to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindSmallestCard</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findsmallestcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 14:34:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findsmallestcard/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994)
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Similar Activites FindOldestPenny, FindYoungestStudent
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition. CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, SieveOfErastothenes
Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to find the smallest card (e.g. lowest value card) in a collection of 16 cards. The notion of a &amp;ldquo;two-card comparator&amp;rdquo; is discussed as part of the process (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindOldestPenny</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 13:09:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava, with consultation from Brett A Becker.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Similar Activities FindSmallestCard, FindYoungestStudent
Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to find the oldest penny in a pile of pennies. This is first done sequentially, with one student trying to determine the oldest penny in a group of 50 pennies. Next, two students are employed, with each student getting a bag of 25 pennies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JigsawPuzzle</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/jigsawpuzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 13:12:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/jigsawpuzzle/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - Overview, Slides 45-52.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  Variations It is theoretically possible to &amp;ldquo;act out&amp;rdquo; the analogy by using an actual puzzle. However, the puzzle needs to be small enough to enable students to complete the puzzle in a reasonable amount of time. This variation is described in (Neeman2006):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PBJinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pbjinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:19:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pbjinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage Communication and Coordination (Core Tier 1) 2. Core Tier 1: Give an example of an ordering of accesses among concurrent activities (e.g., program with a data race) that is not sequentially consistent. [Familiarity]
TCPP Topics Coverage Programming Topics  Comprehend Deadlocks: Understand what a deadlock is, and methods for detecting and preventing them
 Know Data Races: Know what a data race is, and how to use synchronization to prevent it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 12:39:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). Also alluded to by Garcia and (Moore2000).
Variation using a deck of playing cards by (Ghafoor2019):
iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  Similiar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, PipelineSort, sortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, PipelineSort
(Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
(Ghafoor2019):
Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to sort a deck of 16 cards (it is assumed that there are unique numbers) using parallel selection sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OrangeGame</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/orangegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:59:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/orangegame/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link CSUnplugged.Org
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage PD/Communication and Coordination Core Tier 2  Give an example of a scenario in which blocking message sends can deadlock. [Usage]  TCPP Coverage Programming Topics  Comprehend Deadlocks: Understand what a deadlock is, and methods for detecting and preventing them  Recommended Courses  K-12: CSUnplugged recommends this as a K-12 activity Systems/OS: The activity can also be used to introduce the concepts of concurrency and deadlock in undergraduate courses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>