<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perf_2 on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/perf_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perf_2 on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:17:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/perf_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MoreProcessorsNotAlwaysBetter</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to write the statement &amp;ldquo;More Processors Are Not Always The Best&amp;rdquo;, along with the indices of each letter.
 Sequential phase. In the sequential phase, a single student is instructed to first write the statement show above (task 1) and then write the index associated with each letter (0 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindOldestPenny</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 13:09:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava, with consultation from Brett A Becker.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Similar Activities FindSmallestCard, FindYoungestStudent
Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to find the oldest penny in a pile of pennies. This is first done sequentially, with one student trying to determine the oldest penny in a group of 50 pennies. Next, two students are employed, with each student getting a bag of 25 pennies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JigsawPuzzle</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/jigsawpuzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 13:12:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/jigsawpuzzle/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - Overview, Slides 45-52.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  Variations It is theoretically possible to &amp;ldquo;act out&amp;rdquo; the analogy by using an actual puzzle. However, the puzzle needs to be small enough to enable students to complete the puzzle in a reasonable amount of time. This variation is described in (Neeman2006):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 12:39:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). Also alluded to by Garcia and (Moore2000).
Variation using a deck of playing cards by (Bogaerts2014 and Ghafoor2019):
iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  Similiar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, PipelineSort, sortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, PipelineSort
(Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
(Ghafoor2019): ArraysInParallel, CandySorting, FindYoungestStudentInClass, PBJinParalell,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>