<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paper on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/medium/paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paper on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/medium/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ArrayAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
Details Students sitting at desks represent &amp;ldquo;threads&amp;rdquo; on individual cores. Each student has a piece of paper on their desk representing local memory. Prior to the activity, the instructor writes an array on the board, filled with random values (limit 1 through 10 for ease of addition), with indices written underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/paralleladdition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 15:43:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/paralleladdition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994)
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): FindSmallestCard, CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, SieveOfErastothenes, AddLargeNumbers
Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to add a series of 16 random numbers. Each student is given a piece of paper (representing local memory) that only they have access to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ConcertTickets</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/concerttickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 17:54:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/concerttickets/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Kolinkat2001). Modified for a CS1 audience by Gary Lewandowski, Dennis Bouvier, Robert McCartney, Kate Sanders, and Beth Simon in 2007 (Lewandowski2007, Lewandowski2010)
No on-line resources available. See details for description.
Details CS1 Use-Case The following scenario is presented to students entering CS1 on their first day (Lewandowski2010):
 Suppose a Ticket Sale Company sells concert tickets in the following way: When a customer calls and asks for a n seats, the seller (1) finds the n best available seats; (2) marks those n seats as unavailable; and (3) deals with customer payment options and either e-mails ticket receipt or sends tickets to the Will Call Box Office (lets customer pick up tickets day of show).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DesertIslandsAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 15:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Distributed Multiprocessing&amp;rdquo;, Slides 19-25.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  The following questions from (Neeman2006) can be used to stimulate discussion:
 Suppose that each student is on his or her own island far away from everyone else. Are any of them aware of anyone else? Do they know who is at the other end of the phone line?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MatrixAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 09:38:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). In a separate paper (Kitchen1992), the notion of adding numbers in a matrix to illustrate master/worker is alluded to, but not discussed in depth.
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by author (Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
Details Moore describes how to use Matrix Addition to describe the differences between shared memory vs distributed memory systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 12:39:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). Also alluded to by Garcia and (Moore2000).
Variation using a deck of playing cards by (Bogaerts2014 and Ghafoor2019):
iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  Similiar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, PipelineSort, sortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, PipelineSort
(Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
(Ghafoor2019): ArraysInParallel, CandySorting, FindYoungestStudentInClass, PBJinParalell,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SortingNetwork</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:31:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link CSUnplugged.Org
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage N/A
TCPP Coverage Algorithms:  Know Sorting: Observe several sorting algorithms for varied platforms &amp;mdash; together with analyses. Parallel merge sort is the simplest example, but equally simple alternatives for rings and meshes might be covered also; more sophisticated algorithms might be covered in more advanced courses (1 hour)  Recommended Courses  K-12: CSUnplugged recommends this as a K-12 activity. CS1/CS2/DSA: The activity can be used to introduce students to parallel sorting concepts in undergraduate courses, but is inappropriate for large classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>