<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>K_Sorting on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/tcppdetails/k_sorting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in K_Sorting on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:25:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/tcppdetails/k_sorting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OddEvenTranspositionSort</title>
      <link>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/activities/oddeventranspositionsort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:25:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/activities/oddeventranspositionsort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Adam Rifkin (Rifkin1994), with a separate description by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). (Bachelis1994) also presents the sort as a &amp;ldquo;compare-exchange sort&amp;rdquo;. We extrapolate on (Rifkin1994), since it is well described.
No web-link to independent description available. However, (Sivilotti2003) employed the exercise in a summer workshop for middle school girls, and provided a write-up of the activity and slides associated with the activity at his website:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardSorting</title>
      <link>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/activities/cardsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 12:39:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/activities/cardsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). Also alluded to by Garcia and (Moore2000).
Variation using a deck of playing cards by (Ghafoor2019):
iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  Similiar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, PipelineSort, sortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, PipelineSort
(Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
(Ghafoor2019):
Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to sort a deck of 16 cards (it is assumed that there are unique numbers) using parallel selection sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SortingNetwork</title>
      <link>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/activities/sortingnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:31:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suzannejmatthews.github.io/PDC-Unplugged/activities/sortingnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link CSUnplugged.Org
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage N/A
TCPP Coverage Algorithms:  Know Sorting: Observe several sorting algorithms for varied platforms &amp;mdash; together with analyses. Parallel merge sort is the simplest example, but equally simple alternatives for rings and meshes might be covered also; more sophisticated algorithms might be covered in more advanced courses (1 hour)  Recommended Courses  K-12: CSUnplugged recommends this as a K-12 activity. CS1/CS2/DSA: The activity can be used to introduce students to parallel sorting concepts in undergraduate courses, but is inappropriate for large classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>