<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>K_Sorting on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/k_sorting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in K_Sorting on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:39:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/tcppdetails/k_sorting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NondeterministicSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/nondeterministicsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:39:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/nondeterministicsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Paulo A.G. Sivilotti and Scott Pike
Paper and poster available online:
 Details See paper and poster for full details. A high level summary is provided below:
  A group of students are chosen to represent elements in an array. Each student is given a sign/sticker that indicates their position in the array. Each student is also given an index card with a random integer value on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PipelineSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pipelinesort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 12:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pipelinesort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). It was also mentioned in (Kitche1992), but (Maxim1990) is listed as a reference.
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Similiar Exercises: Sorting: OddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, CardSorting, SortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
 Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal of this exercise is to illustrate how sorting can occur in a stream/pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelRadixSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelradixsort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 10:30:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelradixsort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Adam Rifkin (1994). No web-link to independent description available. However, (Sivilotti2003) employed the exercise in a summer workshop for middle school girls, and provided a write-up of the activity and slides associated with the activity at his website
 Slides (includes other activities) PPT 1 Page Synopsis PDF  See papers (Rifkin1994, Sivilotti2003) for additional details.
Similar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, sortingNetwork, cardsorting
Other activities by (Rifki1994, Sivilotti2003) Rifkin1994: oddEvenTranspositionSort</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OddEvenTranspositionSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/oddeventranspositionsort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:25:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/oddeventranspositionsort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Adam Rifkin (Rifkin1994), with a separate description by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). (Bachelis1994) also presents the sort as a &amp;ldquo;compare-exchange sort&amp;rdquo;. We extrapolate on (Rifkin1994), since it is well described.
No web-link to independent description available. However, (Sivilotti2003) employed the exercise in a summer workshop for middle school girls, and provided a write-up of the activity and slides associated with the activity at his website:
 Slides (includes other activities) PPT 1 Page Synopsis PDF  See papers (Rifkin1994, Bachelis1994, Moore2000, Sivilotti2003) for additional details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 12:39:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). Also alluded to by Garcia and (Moore2000).
Variation using a deck of playing cards by (Bogaerts2014 and Ghafoor2019):
iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  Similiar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, PipelineSort, sortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, PipelineSort
(Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
(Ghafoor2019): ArraysInParallel, CandySorting, FindYoungestStudentInClass, PBJinParalell,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SortingNetwork</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:31:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link CSUnplugged.Org
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage N/A
TCPP Coverage Algorithms:  Know Sorting: Observe several sorting algorithms for varied platforms &amp;mdash; together with analyses. Parallel merge sort is the simplest example, but equally simple alternatives for rings and meshes might be covered also; more sophisticated algorithms might be covered in more advanced courses (1 hour)  Recommended Courses  K-12: CSUnplugged recommends this as a K-12 activity. CS1/CS2/DSA: The activity can be used to introduce students to parallel sorting concepts in undergraduate courses, but is inappropriate for large classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>