<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS2 on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/courses/cs2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CS2 on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:01:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/courses/cs2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FlowerJoinAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/flowerjoinanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:01:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/flowerjoinanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Steve Bogaerts (Bogaerts2014).
No link to independent description publicly available. See &amp;ldquo;Details&amp;rdquo; section for more details:
 Details Bogaerts used this analogy to explain the notion of thread join operation. Suppose a parent and their child are out for a walk along a trail in their local park. The child decides to travel off the path to pick flowers. While the parent can go on for some time without the child, eventually they will call out to the child to catch up: &amp;ldquo;Come now, please join me up here&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SurvivorAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/survivoranalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 15:20:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/survivoranalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Steve Bogaerts (Bogaerts2014).
No link to independent description publicly available. See &amp;ldquo;Details&amp;rdquo; section for more details:
 Details This analogy is used to explain the mechanism of locks. While (Bogaerts2014) specifically references the book The Lord of the Flies, not everyone may be familiar with that book (and some who are already familiar may not want to be reminded of it). Instead, it may be useful to explain the following general scenario:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantingTrees</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Described by Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Kolinkat2001). Two introduction questions presented by Steven Bogaerts as part of his &amp;ldquo;real-life analogies&amp;rdquo; (Bogaerts2014, Bogaerts2017).
No public description avaialable. See Details section for more information.
 Details Start with some generals questions from Steven Bogaerts:
 &amp;ldquo;If I can shovel my driveway in 1 hour, how long would you expect it to take if someone equally capable were to help me?&amp;rdquo;
  &amp;ldquo;If one person can dig a hole with a shovel in 100 seconds, how long will it take for 10 people to dig that hole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArrayAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:13:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arrayaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
 Details Students sitting at desks represent &amp;ldquo;threads&amp;rdquo; on individual cores. Each student has a piece of paper on their desk representing local memory. Prior to the activity, the instructor writes an array on the board, filled with random values (limit 1 through 10 for ease of addition), with indices written underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StuffingEnvelopes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:10:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
 Details Prior to the activity, students should be assigned to teams of four. The goal is to discuss different strategies for completing the stack of preparing letters for mailing. In doing the activity, students learn about domain (data) decomposition vs task decomposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StabalizingLeaderElection</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stabalizingleaderelection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 16:15:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stabalizingleaderelection/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Paulo A.G. Sivilotti and Scott Pike
Paper available online:
 Details See paper for full details. This activity demonstrates how an algorithm can recover from data corruption. The students in this activity represent processes in an undirected connected graph. Each process has a unique identifier. The goal is to identify the process with the highest identifier. While the process identifiers themselves are not corruptible, the model assumes that transient faults may occur that can corrupt data values associated with the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelGarbageCollection</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelgarbagecollection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 14:36:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelgarbagecollection/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Paulo A.G. Sivilotti and Scott Pike
Paper and poster available online:
 Details See paper for details. In summary, this activity presents a directed graph with a distinguished vertex (labeled the root). Vertices are connected to each other with some number of edges. The end-goal is determine the set of reachable vertices from the root (&amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo;) and distinguish them from the set of non-reachable vertices (&amp;ldquo;garbage&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NondeterministicSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/nondeterministicsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 13:39:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/nondeterministicsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Paulo A.G. Sivilotti and Scott Pike
Paper and poster available online:
 Details See paper and poster for full details. A high level summary is provided below:
  A group of students are chosen to represent elements in an array. Each student is given a sign/sticker that indicates their position in the array. Each student is also given an index card with a random integer value on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AddLargeNumbers</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/addlargenumbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 10:46:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/addlargenumbers/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994)
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): FindSmallestCard, CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, SieveOfErastothenes, ParallelAddition
 Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to introduce students to how large pairs of numbers in parallel.
Suppose the goal is to add two large numbers (in this example, 534,789,213 and 495,378,388).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/paralleladdition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 15:43:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/paralleladdition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994)
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): FindSmallestCard, CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, SieveOfErastothenes, AddLargeNumbers
 Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to add a series of 16 random numbers. Each student is given a piece of paper (representing local memory) that only they have access to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindSmallestCard</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findsmallestcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 14:34:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findsmallestcard/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994)
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Similar Activites FindOldestPenny, FindYoungestStudent
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition. CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, SieveOfErastothenes
 Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal is to find the smallest card (e.g. lowest value card) in a collection of 16 cards. The notion of a &amp;ldquo;two-card comparator&amp;rdquo; is discussed as part of the process (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MoreProcessorsNotAlwaysBetter</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:17:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/moreprocessorsnotalwaysbetter/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
 Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to write the statement &amp;ldquo;More Processors Are Not Always The Best&amp;rdquo;, along with the indices of each letter.
  Sequential phase. In the sequential phase, a single student is instructed to first write the statement show above (task 1) and then write the index associated with each letter (0 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindOldestPenny</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 13:09:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findoldestpenny/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link This activity was originally proposed by Mary Smith and Srishti Srivastava, with consultation from Brett A Becker.
Paper (Srivastava2019) and slides available on-line.
Similar Activities FindSmallestCard, FindYoungestStudent
 Details See paper for details. In summary, the goal is to find the oldest penny in a pile of pennies. This is first done sequentially, with one student trying to determine the oldest penny in a group of 50 pennies. Next, two students are employed, with each student getting a bag of 25 pennies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParallelRadixSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelradixsort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 10:30:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/parallelradixsort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Adam Rifkin (1994). No web-link to independent description available. However, (Sivilotti2003) employed the exercise in a summer workshop for middle school girls, and provided a write-up of the activity and slides associated with the activity at his website
 Slides (includes other activities) PPT 1 Page Synopsis PDF  See papers (Rifkin1994, Sivilotti2003) for additional details.
Similar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, sortingNetwork, cardsorting
Other activities by (Rifki1994, Sivilotti2003) Rifkin1994: oddEvenTranspositionSort</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SweetenJuice</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sweetenjuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:07:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sweetenjuice/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Mordechai Ben-Ari and Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Ben-Ari1999)
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Ben-Ari1999) for additional details.
 Details The paper uses dramatizations to help students understand algorithmic execution. The paper only describes one such lesson, which is used to introduce the concept of mutual exclusion. The following is a rough summary of the exercise in (Ben-Ari1999):
Two students volunteer to be robots. A drinking glass is placed at a visible point in the classroom, purporting to contain &amp;ldquo;juice&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DesertIslandsAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 15:34:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/desertislandsanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Oklahoma Supercomputing Center for Educaton and Research (OSCER)
&amp;ldquo;Supercomputing in Plain English&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Distributed Multiprocessing&amp;rdquo;, Slides 19-25.
 Available in: PPT and PDF Also described in (Neeman2006)  The following questions from (Neeman2006) can be used to stimulate discussion:
 Suppose that each student is on his or her own island far away from everyone else. Are any of them aware of anyone else? Do they know who is at the other end of the phone line?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SieveOfErastothenes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:56:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sieveoferastothenes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Maxim1990, Bachelis1994). Also described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000) and (Kitchen1992).
No web-link to independent description available. See papers (Bachelis1994, Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, OddEvenTranspositionSort
(Moore2000): CardSorting, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
 Details Suppose the goal is to find all the primes less than n = 1,000. In the serial case, all the numbers from 2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MatrixAddition</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 09:38:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/matrixaddition/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). In a separate paper (Kitchen1992), the notion of adding numbers in a matrix to illustrate master/worker is alluded to, but not discussed in depth.
No web-link to independent description available. See paper (Moore2000) for additional details.
Other activities by author (Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
 Details Moore describes how to use Matrix Addition to describe the differences between shared memory vs distributed memory systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OddEvenTranspositionSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/oddeventranspositionsort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:25:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/oddeventranspositionsort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally Described by Adam Rifkin (Rifkin1994), with a separate description by Michelle Moore (Moore2000). (Bachelis1994) also presents the sort as a &amp;ldquo;compare-exchange sort&amp;rdquo;. We extrapolate on (Rifkin1994), since it is well described.
No web-link to independent description available. However, (Sivilotti2003) employed the exercise in a summer workshop for middle school girls, and provided a write-up of the activity and slides associated with the activity at his website:
 Slides (includes other activities) PPT 1 Page Synopsis PDF  See papers (Rifkin1994, Bachelis1994, Moore2000, Sivilotti2003) for additional details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PBJinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pbjinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:19:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pbjinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Note: The &amp;ldquo;Make a Peanut Butter and Jelly Sandwich&amp;rdquo; serial exercise is an extremely old way to describe how a computer executes a set of instructions. The earliest known description is the &amp;ldquo;Great Peanut Butter Caper&amp;rdquo; by Lewandowski and Morehead in 1998. A variation was presented by Davis and Rebelsky in 2007. Unlike the original described exercises, this activity explores how to put together a Peanut Butter and Jelly sandwich in parallel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CandySorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/candysorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:23:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/candysorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF   CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage Parallel Decomposition (Core Tier 1, Core Tier 2) 1. Core Tier 1: Explain why synchronization is necessary in a specific parallel program. [Usage]
2. Core Tier 1: Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
4. Core Tier 2: Parallelize an algorithm by applying task-based decomposition. [Usage]
Parallel Performance (Elective) 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CardSorting</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 12:39:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/cardsorting/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). Also alluded to by Garcia and (Moore2000).
Variation using a deck of playing cards by (Bogaerts2014 and Ghafoor2019):
iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  Similiar Exercises: Sorting: oddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, PipelineSort, sortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, PipelineSort
(Moore2000): SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, MatrixAddition
(Ghafoor2019): ArraysInParallel, CandySorting, FindYoungestStudentInClass, PBJinParalell,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArraysinParallel</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 11:58:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/arraysinparallel/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link iPDC Modules
 Available in Word and PDF  CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage PD/Parallel Decomposition Core Tier1, Core Tier2 2. Core Tier 1:Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
5.\ Core Tier 2:Parallelize an algorithm by applying data-parallel decomposition. [Usage]
TCPP Coverage Programming Topics  Apply Data parallel: Be able to write a correct data parallel program for shared-memory machines and get speedup, should do an exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FindYoungestStudentInClass</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findyoungeststudentinclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 11:20:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/findyoungeststudentinclass/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Chitra P (iPDC Modules)
 Available in Word and PDF  Similar Activities FindOldestPenny, FindSmallestCard
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage PD/Parallel Decomposition Core Tier 1 2. Identify opportunities to partition a serial program into independent parallel modules. [Familiarity]
TCPP Topics Coverage Algorithms Topics  Know Selection: Observe algorithms for finding order statistics, notably min and max. Understand that selection can always be accomplished by sorting but that direct algorithms may be simpler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SortingNetwork</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:31:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/sortingnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link CSUnplugged.Org
CS2013 Knowledge Unit Coverage N/A
TCPP Coverage Algorithms:  Know Sorting: Observe several sorting algorithms for varied platforms &amp;mdash; together with analyses. Parallel merge sort is the simplest example, but equally simple alternatives for rings and meshes might be covered also; more sophisticated algorithms might be covered in more advanced courses (1 hour)  Recommended Courses  K-12: CSUnplugged recommends this as a K-12 activity. CS1/CS2/DSA: The activity can be used to introduce students to parallel sorting concepts in undergraduate courses, but is inappropriate for large classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>