<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algo_9 on PDC Unplugged</title>
    <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/algo_9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algo_9 on PDC Unplugged</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pdcunplugged.org/cs2013details/algo_9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantingTrees</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:16:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/plantingtrees/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Described by Yifat Ben-David Kolikant (Kolinkat2001). Two introduction questions presented by Steven Bogaerts as part of his &amp;ldquo;real-life analogies&amp;rdquo; (Bogaerts2014, Bogaerts2017).
No public description avaialable. See Details section for more information.
 Details Start with some generals questions from Steven Bogaerts:
 &amp;ldquo;If I can shovel my driveway in 1 hour, how long would you expect it to take if someone equally capable were to help me?&amp;rdquo;
  &amp;ldquo;If one person can dig a hole with a shovel in 100 seconds, how long will it take for 10 people to dig that hole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StuffingEnvelopes</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 14:10:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/stuffingenvelopes/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Robert Chesebrough and Ivan Turner; the authors cite the 2nd chapter of James Reinders&amp;rsquo; book (see citations) as inspiration for this example.
No link to indepdendent description available. Please see Details section for more information.
 Details Prior to the activity, students should be assigned to teams of four. The goal is to discuss different strategies for completing the stack of preparing letters for mailing. In doing the activity, students learn about domain (data) decomposition vs task decomposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KitchenAnalogy</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/kitchenanalogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 08:40:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/kitchenanalogy/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link The kitchen analogy is a fairly well-known analogy for discussing the memory hierarchy. I am not sure who first described it. If someone knows, please contact me so I can attribute correctly
There are several on-line write-ups about the Kitchen Analogy. We specifically link to a series of blog-posts on the Kitchen Analogy that were posted on the Intel Developers Site in 2015, as it is one of the most well-developed write-ups of the analogy that I have seen thus far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PipelineSort</title>
      <link>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pipelinesort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 12:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pdcunplugged.org/activities/pipelinesort/</guid>
      <description>Original Author/link Originally described by Gregory F. Bachelis, David A. James, Bruce R. Maxim and Quentin F. Stout (Bachelis1994). It was also mentioned in (Kitche1992), but (Maxim1990) is listed as a reference.
No link to independent description publicly available. Please see details section for a synopsis.
Similiar Exercises: Sorting: OddEvenTranspositionSort, ParallelRadixSort, CardSorting, SortingNetwork
Other activities by authors (Bachelis1994): ParallelAddition, FindSmallestCard, SieveOfErastothenes, OddEvenTranspositionSort, CardSorting
 Details From (Bachelis1994): The goal of this exercise is to illustrate how sorting can occur in a stream/pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>